Whyte, William Foote Additional Papers /4149
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
William Foote Whyte Additional Papers
1941-1991
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Whyte, William Foote
/4149
22 cubic feet
22 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
3108539
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, January 13, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 03, 2016
Biographical / Historical
William Foote Whyte (June 27, 1914 July 16, 2000) was a sociologist chiefly known for his ethnographic study in urban sociology, Street Corner Society.
Whyte, from an upper middle class background, showed an early interest in writing, economics and social reform. After graduating from Swarthmore College, he was selected for the Junior Fellows program, where his landmark research was done. After his research in Boston, he entered the sociology doctoral program at the University of Chicago. Street Corner Society was published by the University of Chicago Press in 1943. He spent a year teaching at the University of Oklahoma, but developed polio in 1943 and spent two years in physical therapy at the Warm Springs Foundation. Rehabilitation was only partially successful; Whyte walked with a cane for the rest of his life, and used two arm crutches in his later years.
He briefly returned to the University of Chicago in 1944, then joined the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University in 1948, remaining at Cornell for the remainder of his career. He worked for social reform and social change, directing his efforts toward "empowering the disenfranchized and narrowing the gap between rich and poor." He studied industrial and agricultural workers and workers' cooperatives in Venezuela, Peru, Guatemala and in the Basque region of Spain, as well as in the United States. He authored hundreds of articles and 20 books including an autobiography. He is considered a pioneer in industrial sociology.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4058: William Foote Whyte Office Records /4087: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4094: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4102: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4151: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers
Whyte, William Foote,1914-2000.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.
3108539
- A Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Academic Advisory Committee, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Patricia Adler, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- AID, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Alabama, University of, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Alberti, Giorgio, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Alderfer, Clayton P., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Mitchell Allen, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- American Anthro. Assoc., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- American Sociological Association, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Conrad Arensberg, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Dominick R. Argona, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Chris Argyris, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Atteslander, Peter, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Autobiography, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Basque Education Project (potential), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- B Correspondence, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- William L. Batt, Jr., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Joseph Blasi, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Bluestone, Irving, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Sherwood Boehlert, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Robert R. Braun, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Urie Bronfenbrenner, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Severyn Bruyn, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Budget, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Martin Blumer, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Budget, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Martin Blumer, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- C Correspondence, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Cahrs Baldrige Research Project, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- CIP, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Eliot D. Chapple, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Chicago Pneumatic Tool Company, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Center for Economic and Social Justice, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Pirre Clavel, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Clippings, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Cole, Robert, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Conte, Robert, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Cornell Community and Economic Development, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Cornell University Press, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- D Correspondence, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Alfonse D'Amato, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Steven Deustch, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Lewis Dexter, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Wilton S. Dillon, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Dunnington, Richard, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- E Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- EDA Project, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Eddy, Elizabeth, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Elden, Max, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Ellerman, David, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Elling, Ray, Univ. of Conn. Hlth. Ctr., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Elsevier, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Employee Ownership Workshop, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- ESOP Association, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- F Correspondence, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- FEI, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Ferguson, Allen R., 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Ferman, Louis, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Fichter, Joseph H., 1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Fletcher, Sylvia A., 1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Foundation Proposal, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Foundation for Enterprise Develop., 1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Fox, Renee, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Friedland, William H., 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- FEDO, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Ford Foundation, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Foundation, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- G Correspondence, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Galbraith, John, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Gardner, Burleigh B., 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Gates, Jeffrey, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Dr. James Green, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Green, Mark, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Davydd Greenwood, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Greenwood and Harkavy, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Guerard, Jean-Claude, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Guest, Robert, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Gustaven, Bjorn, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Gutierrez-Johnson, Ana, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- H Correspondence, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Hammer, Tove, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Ira Harkavy, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Hawaii, Japan, China Trip, Spring 1982 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Hildebrand, Peter E., 1982 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Homans, George C., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Horowitz, Irving L., 1986 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Horton, Douglas, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Hughes Helen and Everett, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- I Correspondence, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- ILR Annual Report, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- ILR Publications, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- ILR Report October 1988 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- INCAE, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- IRRA - 1962 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Inquiries, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- J Correspondence, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Japanese Seminar Summer 1983 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Misc., 1987 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Kawabuchi, Hideo, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Robert Keidel Assoc., 1988 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Kennedy, Timothy, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Kochan, Thomas A., 1988 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Kostmayer. Peter, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Kurland, Norman, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- L Correspondence, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Lazes, Peter, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Legarreta, Isabel, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- U.S. Dept. of Labor, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Levinson Foundation, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Lundberg, Craig, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Lundine, Stanley, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Luster, Martin Political Corresp., 1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- M Correspondence, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Dr. Matos, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Tom Mailey, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Meek, Chris '75, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Menke, John, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Metrocenter, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Miller, Roberta (Cossa), 1980 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Mondragon, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Mondragon Trip 1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- David G. Moore, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Moynihan, Daniel, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Mc-Mac Correspondence, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- McClaughry, John, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- McHugh, Matthew, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- N Correspondence, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Orlandella, Ralph Correspondence, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- National Coop Bank, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- O Correspondence, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- O and O, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- O'Connor, Joyce, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Oxford University Press, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- P Correspondence, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Pace of Philadelphia, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Larry A. Pace, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Park, Peter, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Parass Conference, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Participation Drafts (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Par-Joint Paper with Greenwood/Haravy, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Participatory Action Research (Box 4, Folder 8)
- University of PA Conference, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Gil Pruess, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Pews Academic Advisory Council, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- PEWS, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- (PEWS) Planning Committee ('89), 1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- PEWS 1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- PEWS Research 1988 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- PEWS - 1987 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- PEWS Research, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- PIC 1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- PEWS/CIS, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Massachusetts Statement (J. Simmons) 1987 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- PEWS - Trico, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- PEWS 1986 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- PEWS 1984 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- PEWS 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Q Correspondence, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- R Correspondence, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Rank Xerox, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Research, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Riesman, David, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Prof. Myron Roomkin Kellogg Sch. Of Mgmt., 1988 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Rose, Michael, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Rosell, Steven, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Rosen, Corey (NCEO), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Rosen, Corey, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Rossi, Peter H., 1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Rothschild Whitt, Joyce, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Roy, Donald, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Ruano, Sergio, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- SA -- SL, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- SBA, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Sage Publications, Inc., 1982-1990 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Warner, W. Lloyd, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Sayles, Leonard, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Reports on Shanghai Visit, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Simmons, John, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Simons, Gene R., 1989 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Sloan Foundation Proposal, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- SM -- SZ, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Soberon, Luis, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Social Theory for Action - Book, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Soc. For App. Anth. Career Achievement Award, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Society for Applied Anthropology Confer. March 1991 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Stern, Robert, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Strauss, George, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Street Corner Society, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Department of States, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Svejnar Project, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- T Correspondence, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Erick Trist, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Thomas, Robert J., 1991 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- U Correspondence, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Umbach, Andrea (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Street Corner Soc. Boelen Controversy, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Uphoff, Norman, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- V Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Vidich, Arthur J., 1991 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- W Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Wenner = Green Foundation Nunez del P., 1975 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Westrum, Ron, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Whyte, Martin King, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Annual Reports W. F. Whyte, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Whyte (Personal) (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Whyte (Personal), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Whyte - (Personal), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Whyte, WM. F. Books and Articles Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- WFW - Retirement, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Wisman, Jon D., 1990 (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Woodworth, Warner, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- The World Bank, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Worker Participation (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Worthy, James C., 1992 (Box 5, Folder 48)
- X Correspondence, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Y Correspondence, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Yamanaka, Keiko, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 51)
- Z Correspondence, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 52)
- A Challenge to Political Scientists, Amer. Pol. Sc. Rev., 1943 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- A Field in Search Focus, ILR Rev. Vol. 18 No. 3/4/65, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Age Grading of the Plan Indians, Man, May-June 1944 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- American Hospital Assoc. "Conference Techniques" (Box 6, Folder 4)
- "An Intercultural Context for Organizational Research, Org. BEH. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Applying Behavioral Science Research to Mgmt. Problems (Box 6, Folder 6)
- "Aunt effie and the Brass Nation, Vol. 205 5 8/67, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- "Bldg. Better Org. Models, "Essays in Ind. Rels. Theory, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- "Can he Social Sciences he be Useful, The Amer. Scholar, Summer 1944 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- "The Collective Bargaining Process," HO, Vols. 9-10,1,1950 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- "Common Management Strategies in Ind. Rels," (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Community Participation in LA Leading to Social Change and (Box 6, Folder 12)
- "Conflict and Cooperation American Ethologist Vol. 2,2, May, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Conversation (WFW) Organizational DYN. (Box 6, Folder 14)
- "Corner Boys: A Study of Clique Beh," Amer. Jrnl. Of Soc. 3/41, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- "Culture Change and Stress in Rural Peru" (Box 6, Folder 16)
- "Culture, Ind. Rels. And Econ. Dev.:" ILR Rev. (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Describes Common Culture Pattern of Annual Meetings (Box 6, Folder 18)
- "Do Cultural Diff. Affects Workers Att.?, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- "Economic Incentives and Human Relations Harvard Business Rev. March-April 1952 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- The Elusive Phenomenon, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Emergence of Employee Owned Firms in U.S., 1955 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- "Engineers and Workers Human Organization Vol. 14,4 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Extra departmental Enterprise, Society, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- "Facing the Foreman's Problem" Applied Anthropology, IV 4, Spring 1945 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Financing New York City, The Amer. Acad. Of Political and Soc. SC. 1935 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Framework for the Analysis of Ind. Rels.," ILR Review, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- The Grievance Process (Box 6, Folder 28)
- "Heroes, Homework and Ind. Growth", COL., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- "How do you Know if the Informant is Telling the Truth?" (Box 6, Folder 30)
- "Human Problems of U.S. Enterprise in LA ILR Conf. Report (Box 6, Folder 31)
- "Human Rels. In the Rest. Ind." 1948, McGraw Hill Book Co. (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Human Rels. In Ind." The Delphian Quarter-Vol. 40, 2, Spring (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Human Relations Theory Harvard Business Rev. Sept. Oct. 1956 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- "Human Relations Theory" Harvard Business Rev. Sept. - Oct. 1956 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- "Imitation of Innov.: Refl. Of the Dev. Of Peru," Adm. Science, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- In Support of Voluntary Employee Ownership (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Incentives for Productivity: Bundy Tubing, Applied Anthro, Vol. 72, Spring 1948 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- The Industrial Comm. In Peru, Annals, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- "Instruction and Res.: A Challenge to Pol. Scien." Amer. Pol. Sc. (Box 6, Folder 40)
- "Intercultural Comm.: A Guide to Men of Action, Ho, 19,1, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Industrial and Organizational Relations, Encyclopedia Britannica, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 42)
- "An Intercultural Context for Org. Res." OB Behavior: Theory, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 43)
- "Interviewing for Org. Res.", HO 12,2 Summer 1953 (Box 6, Folder 44)
- "Latest Dev. In HR" Management Record, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 45)
- "Leadership and Group Participation" Bulletin 24 ILR (Box 6, Folder 46)
- "Los Valores y el Crecimiento Economico en el Peru, Flores", 1963 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  Scope and Contents
  Spanish
- "Methods for the Study of HR in Industry" Burleigh Gardner (Box 6, Folder 48)
- "Models for Bldg. and Changing Organizations, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Mondragon System pf Workers Prod. Cooperatives, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 50)
- "Must you Tell a Funny Story?", 1968 (Box 6, Folder 51)
- "Need and Opportunities for Ind. Rels. Res. Reprint 125, ILR (Box 6, Folder 52)
- "On Asking indirect Questions (Box 6, Folder 53)
- "On Language and Culture," Whyte/Braun Reprint 253, ILR (Box 6, Folder 54)
- On Making the Most of Participant Observation, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 55)
- On Street Corner Society Contributions to Urban Sociology, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 56)
- "Organizational and Motivation of Management," Industrial Productivity (Box 6, Folder 57)
- "Organizations for the 1980's, in Man and the Future of Organizations (Box 6, Folder 58)
- Participatory Approach to AG Research and Development (Box 6, Folder 59)
- "Patterns of Interaction in Union Management Relations" (Box 6, Folder 60)
- "People in Petroleum" (Box 6, Folder 61)
- "Pidgeon's, Persons and Piece Rates," Psychology Today April 1972 (Box 6, Folder 62)
- "Pity the Personnel Man," Advanced Management, Oct. -Dec. 1944 (Box 6, Folder 63)
- "The Man in the Middle Applied Anthro, 4, 2, Spring 1945 (Box 6, Folder 64)
- "Politics and Ethics Amer. Pol. Sc. Review XL, 2, April 1946 (Box 6, Folder 65)
- "Potatoes, Peasants and Professors", 1977 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- "Problems of Industrial Sociology, Social Problems, Oct. 1956 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Proyecto de Estudio de Cambios En Pueblos Peruanos-Matos-WFW Lima, 1966 LAP Reprint (Box 7, Folder 3)
- "Reflections on my Work" American Behavioral Scientist, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Research Methods for the Study of Conflict and Cooperation, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- The Role of the US Professor in Dev. Countries, the American Sociologist Feb. 1969 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- "Rural Peru - Peasants as Activists" (Box 7, Folder 7)
- "Semantics and Industrial Relations," HO, 8,2, Spring 1949 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- "Sicilian Peasant Society," American Anthropologist, Jan.-Mar. 1944 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- A Slum Sex Code," Amer. Jr. of Soc. XLIX, July 1943 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- "Ch. 12-small Groups and Large Organizations" (Box 7, Folder 11)
- "Social Organization in the Slums," Amer. Sociological Review, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- "Social Science and Ind. Rels.," Personnel Jan. 1951 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- "The Social Structure of the Restaurant," Amer. Jr. Sociology, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Solving the Hotel's Human Problems," The Hotel Monthly, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- "The Strategy of Union Management Cooperation" (Box 7, Folder 16)
- "Supervisory Leadership: An International Comparison," CIOs, XIII, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Theory, Methods and Strategy in OB Research C.I.S.R. Spring '76, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- "Thoughtways of Foreign Policy," The Nation May 30, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- "Toward an Integrated Theory of Organizational Behavior," IRRA, 16th Annual Meeting 1963 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Toward a New Strategy for RandD Ag.: Helping Small Farmers (Box 7, Folder 21)
- "Union-Management Cooperation: Toronto Case." APP. Anthro, Summer/'47, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- "Who Does What with Whom, and Where?" Swarthmore College Bulletin Oct. 1960 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- "Who Goes Union and Why" Personnel Journal Dec. 1944 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Index (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Augusto del Valle, Manager of FEDEPAPA, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Bibliography on Participation -and- Self-Management, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Cornell-Jamestown Relations: Research and Technical Assistance Possibilities, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- The Development of Industrial Democracy in Mondragon - Ana Johnson (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Field Methods in Sociology (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Government Bureaucracy in Peru (Box 7, Folder 31)
- The Huasahuasi Case (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Joint Payoff Relations and Multi-Objective Planning (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Joint Payoffs and Multi-Objective Planning (Part 2) (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Limited Factors Intervention Strategy and Multi-Objective Program Planning (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Looking for the Third Dimension: Toward a New Model of International Research and Development in Agriculture, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Mapping the Territory Theoretically: rough Sketch for a Theoretical Framework (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Notes for Transforming the Shut Down Plant, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Organizational Aspects of the Utilization of Science and Technology (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Organizational Behavior Research: Where do we go from Here? (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Organizing for Local Economic Development (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Ownership, Control and Participation, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Planning for CIP's Socio Economic Program (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Participant Observation and Related Research Methods, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Quality of Working Life Program (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Saving Jobs Through Employee Ownership (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Seed Production Systems: Notes for a Colombia Project, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 47)
- The Social Lessons of Project Puebla, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 48)
- Social Sciences in 2000 A.D. (Box 7, Folder 49)
- The Elusive Phenomenon, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 50)
- The Logic of Farming systems, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 51)
- The Trend Toward Multi-Cropping, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 52)
- Toward New Models for Research and Development in Agriculture, 1973-1975 (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Toward a New Strategy for Research and Development in Agriculture (Box 7, Folder 54)
- Worker Participation in Peru: The Industrial Community (Box 7, Folder 55)
- Notes on Variables, Structure, Process and Science, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 56)
- Intervention for Institutional Goals (Box 7, Folder 57)
- Beyond Skinner (Box 7, Folder 58)
- A Multiple Goals Development Strategy (Box 7, Folder 59)
- A Strategy for Science and Technology in Developing Countries (Box 7, Folder 60)
- Conflict and Cooperation in Andean Peasant Communities (Box 7, Folder 61)
- Peru - W. F. Whyte, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- On Making the Most of Participant Observation (Box 8, Folder 2)
- W.F. Whyte, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- W.F. Whyte, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- W.F. Whyte, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- William F. Whyte, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Peru MSS, 1967-1969 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Filing To Do (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Misc. (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Papers Written on Grant, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- AG. Research and Development Monogr., 1981 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- "An Intercultural Context to Economic, Political and Military Relations, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Bibliography on Parti. And Self-Management, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Birth of the Mohawk Valley Comm. Corp. (Weinhberg Sem. Nov. 1976) (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Breman - J.R. Whitt, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Buying Your Job: Reconsiderations By Rns and THH, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- The Collec. Org.: An Alternative to Rat.- Bureaucratic Models JRW, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Confronting the Conglomerate Merger Menace - Testimony (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Congressional Record Statement - Whyte, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Effects of Employee ownership on Org. Identi., Employ Job (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Doing Field Work ASA Panel, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Draft Statement on Legislation, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Emergence of Employee Owned Firms in U.S., 1977 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Employee Ownership: Hammer and Stern, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Employee Ownership and Economic Democracy Whyte and Blazi, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Employee Ownership in the Restructuring of the American Economy 1984 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Employee Ownership: Policy Issues for Union Leaders - WFW, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Employee Ownership: Implications Hammer and Stern, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Employee Ownership: Saving Businesses, Jobs Commentary Sp. 1982 (Box 9, Folder 20)